gm.com 2018-06-20

# Privacy Statement | GM.com

**General Motors Company U.S. Consumer Privacy Statement  
**Last modified: January, 2018  

**Scope**  
Your privacy is important to General Motors Company (“GM” or “we”) as is your trust in GM’s products and services. We want you to know that the information you share with us will be treated with care. This Privacy Statement addresses what personal information we collect and how we handle the personal information shared with us.

This Privacy Statement applies to personal information we obtain from and about individuals interacting with GM and its websites, products and services. It does not apply to personal information we obtain in our capacity as an employer.  This Privacy Statement covers all GM controlled subsidiaries and affiliates in the U.S. except for General Motors Financial Company, Inc. which has its own Privacy Statement.  Certain products and services may be subject to other privacy statements independently or in combination with this Privacy Statement and should be reviewed by the consumer, for example  OnStar, LLC’s can be viewed at  <https://www.onstar.com/web/portal/privacy>, Maven Drive, LLC’s can be viewed at <https://www.mavendrive.com/#!/legal/privacy-policy>, and mobile applications may have separate privacy statements, as described in the Mobile Applications section below.

Key points about our information practices

**Collection**

| 

We may collect information about you and your vehicle, such as name, address, email address, phone number, vehicle identification number (VIN) and vehicle performance data through your use of our products or services, and through GM affiliates, dealers, GM licensees for consumer merchandise, GM partners and others who provide information to us.  _**See below to learn more.** _  
  
---|---  
  
**Use**

| 

We may use your information to provide products and services, to maintain customer relationships, for safety and product research purposes, to provide customer and vehicle support and service, and for marketing.   _ **See below to learn more.**_  
  
**Sharing**

| 

We may share your information as required by law, within GM, with our GM controlled subsidiaries and affiliates, with GM dealers, with GM licensees, with our service providers, and with our business partners. _**See below to learn more.**_  
  
**Choices**

| 

You have choices regarding how we use and share your information for marketing and other purposes. _**See below to learn more.** _  
  
**Cookies and Tracking**

| 

We may use cookies, pixel tags, web beacons and similar tracking technologies to help provide our products and services, understand and customize your preferences, and display relevant advertising. _  **See below to learn more.**_  
  
**Mobile Applications**

| 

GM has developed certain mobile applications that you may download to your mobile device or vehicle (“GM Applications”). When you download a GM Application, there may be an opportunity for you to provide us with or for us to obtain information about you or your vehicle. _**See below to learn more.**_  
  
**Third Party Products and Services**

| 

Through the use of GM products and services, you may be able to access third party services, applications and websites not controlled by GM or covered by this Privacy Statement. _**See below to learn more.**_  
  
**GM Dealers**

| 

GM and GM dealers are separate legal entities with their own privacy practices. For questions about your dealer's privacy practices including opting out of marketing communications from your dealer, please contact your dealer directly. _**See below to learn more.**_  
  
**Access and Update**

| 

You may access your online accounts to update your information or you may contact us to learn about how to do so. _**See below to learn more.**_  
  
**California Privacy Rights**

| 

California residents have certain rights regarding the personal information we disclose to third parties for their own marketing purposes. _**See below to learn more.**_  
  
**Security Measures**

| 

We maintain reasonable and adequate security controls to protect your information and require our service providers by contract to do the same. _**See below to learn more.**_  
  
**Retention**

| 

We keep information for as long as necessary to provide our products and services, operate our business, and comply with legal obligations. _**See below to learn more.**_  
  
**Children's Privacy**

| 

GM websites do not target or knowingly collect any information from children under the age of 13 _. **See below to learn more.**_  
  
**International Data Transfers**

| 

We maintain appropriate protections for cross-border transfers as required by law for international data transfers. _**See below to learn more.**_  
  
**Contact Us**

| 

If you have concerns or questions regarding GM's consumer privacy practices or this Privacy Statement, please contact us at 1-866-MYPRIVACY (1-866-697-7482). _**See below to learn more.**_  
  
**Changes**

| 

We may update this Privacy Statement from time to time. We will do so by posting additions or modifications to this page. _**See below to learn more.**_  
  
**Information Collected**

 _  
_

As you interact with GM, there may be opportunities for you to provide us with your information. Additionally, we may collect certain information about you or your vehicle as further described below.

You may provide us with information about you or your vehicle through a number of sources: GM websites, applications, product and related events, surveys, social media platforms, sweepstakes entries and through our customer call centers.  We also collect information that is publicly available.  For example, we may collect publicly available information you submit to a blog, a chat room, or a social media platform like Facebook, Twitter or Google+ and we may use your information for the purposes set out in this privacy statement.  GM engages with consumers on multiple social media platforms and if you contact us on one of our social media pages, request assistance via social media or otherwise direct us to communicate with you via social media, we may contact you via direct message or use other social media tools to interact with you. In these instances, your interactions with us are governed by this privacy statement as well as the privacy policy of the social media platform you use.

We also receive information about you through vehicle sales records provided by your dealer and we may obtain, with your consent, data obtained from your vehicle’s Event Data Recorder (“EDR”) as described in your owner’s manual (i.e., how various systems in your vehicle operate, the speed and distance of your vehicle). For additional information about EDR data, please see your owner’s manual. We also may obtain information about you and your vehicle from GM affiliates, dealers, GM licensees for consumer merchandise, GM partners (for example, credit card bank partners) and other sources such as companies that provide lists of potential vehicle purchasers and current owners, if such companies are permitted to share your information with us pursuant to their privacy statements. We may combine information that we receive from the various sources described in this Privacy Statement, including third-party sources, with information you provide and use or share it for the purposes identified below.

The types of information that GM collects about you may include, but are not limited to:

  * contact information (such as name, address, city, state and ZIP code, email address and telephone number)
  * payment information (such as your credit card number, CVV code and expiration date)
  * information about your vehicle (such as license plate number, vehicle identification number (VIN), make, model, model year, selling dealer, servicing dealer, date of purchase or lease, the lease/financing term, service history, mileage, oil/battery status, fuel or charging history, electrical system function, gear status, and diagnostic trouble codes)
  * information about your connected devices (such as mobile phone, computer, or tablet) and how you interact with our products, services, apps and websites (such as IP address, browser type, unique device identifier, cookie data, and associated identifying and usage information
  * demographic information (such as gender, date of birth, marital status and household composition)
  * marketing profile information (such as when you plan to purchase or lease; the vehicle in which you're interested)
  * photographs and videos such as those that you may submit for contests, sweepstakes and social sharing
  * relationships you have with GM in addition to the purchase and servicing of your vehicle (such as through a GM Rewards Card, OnStar or Maven etc.)
  * incentive eligibility verification information (such as college name, branch of service or credit union name for vehicle purchase programs)
  * Social Security Number (in limited circumstances GM may collect SSN, for example if you win a sweepstakes or receive compensation that must be reported for government tax purposes)
  * investor information (name, address, phone number and email address)
  * stockholder services information (such as account information)

**Use**  
The information GM collects about you and your vehicle may be used:

  * to provide products and services and maintain customer relationships
  * to improve the quality, safety, and security of our products and services
  * to administer your account(s) and process your payments for products and services
  * to operate our websites and applications, including online registration processes
  * to facilitate and support GM dealer and supplier diversity programs and GM grant programs
  * to autofill data fields on our websites to improve your online experience
  * to develop new products and services, including connected, autonomous and car-sharing products and services
  * to provide customer and vehicle support and service (such as recall information)
  * for warranty administration and validation
  * to provide information and product updates
  * to evaluate vehicle performance and safety as described in the vehicle owner manual
  * for research, evaluation of use, and troubleshooting purposes
  * to verify eligibility for vehicle purchase or incentive programs
  * for marketing and analytics purposes
  * to support the electronic signature and delivery process between you and your dealer
  * to customize and improve communication content
  * to comply with legal, regulatory or contractual requirements

Communications with you in connection with these uses may be via mail, telephone, e-mail, text message, social media and other electronic messages, through the in-vehicle OnStar system or via our websites and applications.  GM may send you text messages using an automated telephone dialing system to the mobile phone number you have provided if you have opted into receive text messages. Opting into receive text messages is not a requirement to buy products or services from GM, and message and data rates may apply.  See “Choices” below to learn how to manage your communication preferences.

You may choose to forward information from one of our websites or emails to another person through our Forward to a Friend program. Email addresses submitted to our E-card or other Forward to a Friend programs will not be captured for later use in marketing unless the recipient opts into receiving additional marketing materials from GM.

**Sharing**  
GM may share the information it collects about you or your vehicle in the following instances:

  * within GM, with our GM controlled subsidiaries and affiliates, with GM dealers and with GM licensees; however, transaction information regarding your GM Card will not be shared with GM dealers.
  * with our services providers who work on our behalf and who do not have an independent right to use the information to which they have access or that we disclose to them
  * with our business partners for GM marketing activities, business partner marketing activities or both
  * with third parties for research and development purposes (such as university research institutes for improving highway safety)
  * in connection with the sale, transfer or financing of a significant part of a GM business or its assets, including any such activities associated with a bankruptcy proceeding
  * when we believe in good faith that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights, protect your safety or the safety of others, investigate fraud or respond to a law enforcement request
  * as required by law, such as in conjunction with a subpoena, government inquiry, litigation, dispute resolution or similar legal process

Apart from the purposes listed above, GM will not share information about you or your vehicle with other third parties for their independent use without your prior consent..

**Choices**  
If you do not want to receive unsolicited marketing communications from GM, please visit our [Consumer Preference System website](https://www.gmcontactpreferences.com/ "Consumer Preference System website") at [www.gmcontactpreferences.com](https://www.gmcontactpreferences.com/ "www.gmcontactpreferences.com"). This will allow you to opt out of unsolicited marketing telephone and email communications and/or to change previously submitted opt-out preferences. You can also call 1-866-MYPRIVACY (1-866-697-7482) to opt out of direct mail communications, as well as telephone and email communications, and/or to change previously submitted opt-out preferences.

If you opt out of receiving marketing communications from GM, your personal information will not be used for marketing, but may still be used for the other purposes described in this Privacy Statement (such as vehicle support and service).

If you have subscribed to a particular email newsletter or other communication (such as My GMLINK Service Reminders), you should follow the instructions in the email or on a related website to unsubscribe.

If you have opted into receiving text messages from GM, you should follow the opt-out instructions in that specific text message program if you wish to opt-out.  If you have opted into any of our text message programs and you later decide to change your phone number or cancel your phone plan you should immediately opt-out of any text message programs and re-opt in with your new phone number if you wish to continue to receive text messages from GM.  This will help us ensure we continue to honor your preferences and text the correct phone number.  

**Cookies/Tracking Technologies**  
GM may use cookies, pixel tags, web beacons and other tracking technologies on our websites, applications, email messages and advertisements to gather information about your visit (such as demographic data, browser type, IP address, pages visited, activities conducted on the page, and the day and time of your visit). Using cookies provides benefits to you, such as allowing you to maintain your account login information or contact information on Request a Quote forms between visits, or locating a nearby dealer. In addition, we use information gathered from cookies to autofill fields on forms such as the city, state or zip code associated with your IP address. This information can be corrected by you before submitting any form or inquiry or you can disable the cookie as discussed below and the information will not be collected.

We place pixel tags and web beacons in our emails to measure the effectiveness of our email campaigns by identifying the individuals who open or act upon an email message, when an email message is opened, how many times an email message is forwarded, the type of software, device, operating system and browser used to deliver the email and any URL accessed through our email message.

To measure site activity, provide a better user experience, and tailor our marketing communications, we or our service providers or business partners may compile information from the cookies, pixel tags, web beacons or other technologies on our websites.  This information may be combined with other information collected online or offline about you, including data provided by third party sources, and may be used or shared for the purposes described in this Privacy Statement.  We may also allow third party advertising and personalization partners to use this information to develop personalized content and appropriate advertising based on your visits over time on GM web sites and non-GM web sites.  This information may also be used to evaluate our online advertising campaigns or to tailor promotions and other marketing messages to you across your devices.

At this time, we do not honor “do no track” signals from a web site browser. However, you may refuse or delete cookies. Please refer to your browser Help instructions to learn more about cookies and other technologies and how to manage their use. If you elect to refuse or delete cookies, you will need to repeat this process if you use another computer, or change browsers. If you choose to decline cookies, some of the functionality of a website may be impaired.

GM adheres to the Digital Advertising Alliance's Self-Regulatory Principles for Online Behavioral Advertising (www.AboutAds.info).  If you do not wish to receive personalized advertising or content from us while visiting GM web sites, you may click on the AdChoices icon and/or link located at the bottom of the web site page or the [Digital Advertising Alliance’s Opt-Out page](http://www.aboutads.info/choices). If you do not wish to receive personalized advertising or content from us on non-GM websites, please visit the [Digital Advertising Alliance’s Opt-Out page](http://www.aboutads.info/choices) or click on the AboutAds icon on a GM advertisement and follow the instructions on how to opt out.  Opting out of relevant advertising will not opt you out of all advertising, but rather only those advertisements that are personalized to your interests by GM or its agents or representatives.

**Mobile Applications**  
GM has developed certain mobile applications that you may download to your mobile device or vehicle (“GM Applications”). When you download a GM Application, there may be an opportunity for you to provide us with or for us to obtain information about you or your vehicle. Each GM Application will display a separate Privacy Statement that will inform you about how any information is collected, used and shared via the application and how to decline such use or uninstall the application.

Through the Infotainment system, GM may also offer applications developed by third parties (“3rd Party Application”). When you download a 3rd Party Application to your mobile device or vehicle, the 3rd Party Application may collect information about you in connection with your download or use of that application. GM is not responsible for the collection or use of information by 3rd Party Applications. We recommend that you carefully review the privacy statement of each 3rd Party Application prior to downloading or using them.

**Third Party Services, Applications and Websites**  
Through the use of GM products and services, you may be able to access third party services, applications and websites not controlled by GM or covered by this Privacy Statement, such as those belonging to GM dealers, GM licensees, co-branded websites offered in conjunction with a business partner, or independent product review sites. We recommend that you carefully review the Privacy Statement of other third party services, applications and websites before providing any personal information.

**GM Dealers    **    
GM and GM dealers are separate legal entities with their own privacy practices. For questions about your dealer's privacy practices including opting out of marketing communications from your dealer, please contact your dealer directly.

When you buy or lease a vehicle from a GM dealer, the dealer will share your information with GM.  Please be aware that each dealer operates as a separate legal entity and you should read the dealer’s privacy statement to ensure that you understand its privacy practices and procedures. Additionally, because the GM dealer often is the first contact with you, the dealer can answer any questions you may have about its privacy practices. While GM encourages its dealers to ensure full compliance with all applicable privacy legislation and has provided information to our dealers relating to privacy obligations, GM is not responsible for dealers’ compliance with applicable law.

When completing a purchase or lease agreement or signing a service repair order with the GM dealer, you should be provided with information describing the dealership's privacy practices and related policies that explain that certain personal information that you provide to the dealer may be shared with GM or others in accordance with this Statement.

**Access and Update**  
You may contact us, as provided below, to learn about how to access, review, correct, update, or delete the information about you in our records.  We may need to retain certain information for recordkeeping purposes, to complete any transactions that you began prior to your request, or for other purposes as required or permitted by applicable law. 

To have your mail, email or telephone information updated please call one of the following Customer Assistance Centers that is specific to your vehicle:

Buick:           1-800-521-7300  
Cadillac:         1-800-458-8006  
Chevrolet:     1-800-222-1020  
GMC:            1-800-462-8782  
Saturn:        1-800-553-6000  
HUMMER:      1-866-486-6376  
Pontiac:       1-800-762-2737

For inquiries about how the information you submit to the Investor Information portion of GM’s website or to GM Stockholder Services is handled, please call 313-667-1432.

You may correct GM Rewards Cards contact information, such as name, address, phone number and email address, by logging onto the Account portion of the website listed on the back of your card. You can also call the Customer Center for your Account.

  * BuyPower Card 888-316-2390
  * GM Flexible Earnings Card 800-388-9107
  * GM Extended Family Card 800-419-6698
  * GM Business Card 800-446-5347

If you have a question or concern about the privacy practices of the BuyPower Card or the GM Card websites, please contact us by sending an email from the Contact Us page or by writing to us at: GM Rewards Card, 100 Renaissance Center, 482-A00-MAR, Detroit, MI 48265.

For GM Family First participants, you may correct your information by contacting your Human Resources representative or updating your information via Socrates. For Vehicle Purchase Plan (“VPP”) participants, you may correct your personal information by visiting the following VPP websites.

  * GM Supplier Discount
  * GM Dealership Employee Discount
  * GM College Discount
  * GM Military Discount
  * Educator Discount  

**California Privacy Rights**  
If you are a California resident you have the right to request information from GM regarding the manner in which GM shares certain categories of your personal information with third parties, for the third parties direct marketing purposes. California law provides that you have the right to submit a request to GM at its designated address and receive the following information:

  * The categories of information GM disclosed to third parties for the third parties' direct marketing purposes during the preceding calendar year; and
  * The names and addresses of third parties that received such information, or if the nature of their business cannot be determined from the name, then examples of the products or services marketed.

You are entitled to receive a copy of this information in a standardized format and the information will not be specific to you individually. You may make such a request by calling 1-866-MYPRIVACY (1-866 697-7482).  

**How we Safeguard Your Information**  
We maintain reasonable and adequate technical, administrative, and physical security and confidentiality measures designed to help protect your information from unauthorized access or acquisition.  We also require by contract (other than in an emergency situations) that third party services providers acting on our behalf or with whom we share your information also undertake to provide such security and confidentiality measures in accordance with industry standards.

**How Long We Keep Your Information**  
We may keep the information we collect for as long as necessary to provide products or services to you, to operate our business, to enable us to communicate with you, for our safety, research, evaluation of use, or troubleshooting purposes, or to satisfy our legal or contractual obligations.  Where required, we will anonymize or dispose of the information we collect when we no longer need it for the uses described above.

**Children’s Privacy**  
GM websites do not target or knowingly collect any information from children under the age of 13.

**International Data Transfers**  
When GM and its controlled subsidiaries and affiliates in the United States, including OnStar, LLC, (“GM U.S.”) receive information from GM controlled subsidiaries and affiliates in Europe, including OnStar Europe Ltd., (collectively “GM Europe companies”), we comply with applicable legal requirements providing adequate protection for the transfer of personal information to countries outside of the EEA or Switzerland. GM U.S. acts as a data processor for its GM controlled subsidiaries and affiliates in Europe (collectively, “GM Europe companies”) by providing data hosting, maintenance, support, and troubleshooting of services, as well as other redundant back office support. GM U.S. acts as a data processor for OnStar Europe Ltd. by providing maintenance, support, and troubleshooting of services, as well as other redundant back office support. GM Europe companies and OnStar Europe Ltd. act as controllers of their own European customer data, and GM U.S. acts as a data processor for these companies.  

We store your information in the United States, the European Economic Area (EEA), and other locations where we or our service providers maintain servers.  With respect to such transfers from the EEA to the United States and other non-EEA jurisdictions, we implement standard contractual clauses and other mechanisms to protect such data.

Individuals that use products or services offered by a GM Europe company or OnStar Europe Ltd. may wish to raise any privacy questions with such company directly, including filing any requests to access European customer data or exercise other privacy rights. Individuals may also raise questions with GM U.S. using the contact details below.

In addition, anonymized and aggregated data from OnStar Europe Ltd. is shared with GM U.S. to evaluate or research the safety, quality, usage, and functionality of vehicles and services, including the OnStar Services; to provide OnStar Europe Ltd. customers with vehicle support and services; and to ensure accurate customer records and maintain customer relationships.  Information also is shared with GM U.S. in order to contact OnStar Europe Ltd. customers about their vehicle or the services, or for marketing purposes, but only if the individual has opted in to receive marketing information.

**How To Contact Us**  
If you have concerns or questions regarding GM's consumer privacy practices or this Privacy Statement you may contact us at 1-866-MYPRIVACY (1-866-697-7482).

**Changes To This Privacy Statement**  
We may update this Privacy Statement from time to time. We will do so by posting additions or modifications to this page.  
Effective date: September 1, 2011  
Last modified: January 5, 2018
